<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apple on</title><link>/categories/apple/</link><description>Recent content in Apple on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Phil Windley’s Technometria | Fixing MacBook Pro Sleep Problems</title><link>/archives/1844/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1844/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here’s how to fix your Macbook Pro’s &lt;a href="http://www.windley.com/archives/2007/10/fixing_macbook_pro_sleep_problems.shtml">busted sleep function&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RSS Reader for Mac – NetNewsWire</title><link>/archives/1830/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1830/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yays! &lt;a href="http://www.newsgator.com/Individuals/NetNewsWire/Default.aspx">NetNewsWire&lt;/a> is now a free download!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I used NNW for ages, a few years ago, but switched to Google Reader after NNW started asking me for my moneys. I find that NNW’s keyboard shortcuts are a lot faster than Google Reader’s, and the general experience is better. Another nice new feature is that news subscriptions sync between multiple copies of NetNewsWire via Newsgator.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seismac</title><link>/archives/1788/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1788/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.suitable.com/tools/seismac.html">SeisMac&lt;/a> is a Mac OS X Cocoa application that makes your MacBook or MacBook Pro into a seismograph. It access your&lt;br>
laptop’s Sudden Motion Sensor in order to display real-time, three-axis acceleration graphs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is really frickin’ cool!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MacBook Pro</title><link>/archives/1777/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1777/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve been really excited by virtualization lately, so of course I’ve been drooling over the potential of the &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/macbookpro/">MacBook Pro&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I considered the Macbook, but decided I enjoyed the large screen and fast graphics of the Powerbook too much to give them up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On Monday I sold my G4 Powerbook to a friend of mine, and ran to the Apple store to buy the MacBook Pro. I spent a full ten minutes explaining how I was buying one “today” to the spiky-haired Mac sales guy, who promptly walked off. I found another salesperson, named Sulgi Kim, who was very nice and gave me a discount on my .Mac subscription along with my new notebook.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My $3000 Carpenter’s Level</title><link>/archives/1759/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1759/</guid><description>&lt;p>This neat &lt;a href="http://pallit.lhi.is/palli/dashlevel/">widget&lt;/a> uses Apple’s Sudden Motion Sensor to display positional information, making my new PowerBook the world’s most expensive carpenter’s level.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Safe-Sleep Your Mac</title><link>/archives/1747/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1747/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the few useful features WinXP has that OSX doesn’t have is “Hibernate”. WinXP is able, upon power loss, to save the contents of a sleeping PC’s RAM to disk, so that the system state and user data isn’t lost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OSX’s sleep feature drains power, albeit slowly. On my work iBook, it can sleep for just about 3 days with no power, before it goes dead.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new Powerbooks have a feature that is called ‘Safe Sleep’, which is pretty much ‘Hibernate’. Since the feature is software-based, it’s fairly easy to &lt;a href="http://www.andrewescobar.com/archive/2005/11/11/how-to-safe-sleep-your-mac/">implement&lt;/a> on non-Powerbook Macs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jed’s Other Poem</title><link>/archives/1737/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1737/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.stewdio.org/jed/">Jed’s Other Poem&lt;/a> (Beautiful Ground) is an unsolicited video for the song of the same name by the band Grandaddy. It is programmed in Applesoft II on a 1979 Apple ][+ with 48k RAM.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MegaManEffect</title><link>/archives/1726/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1726/</guid><description>&lt;p>I really love having my OSX apps launch as enemies from Megaman, complete with the starfield and the bad video game music.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="http://mikezornek.com/cocoa/megamaneffect/">link&lt;/a>] to MegaMan Effect&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Use iTunes as a PDF Repository</title><link>/archives/1722/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1722/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here’s a neat tip: iTunes can manage PDFs, which is handy if you keep a lot of ebooks and reference manuals saved on your system. You can edit the PDF’s ID3 tag for author and genre info, and set up smart playlists as you would for MP3s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="http://www.makezine.com/blog/archive/2005/07/using_pdfs_in_i.html">link&lt;/a>]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Remotely logging AirPort Extreme activity with syslog</title><link>/archives/1713/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1713/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here’s how to set up syslogd on OSX to &lt;a href="http://docs.info.apple.com/article.html?artnum=107993">log base station activity&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that Tiger is a bit different, so you’ll need to refer to &lt;a href="http://www.aaronadams.net/index.php/2005/06/02/configuring_syslogd_to_accept_logs_from">this other article&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mac mini + 1GB RAM = luv</title><link>/archives/1709/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1709/</guid><description>&lt;p>Woot! After adding a gigabyte of RAM to my new &lt;a href="http://apple.com/macmini/">Mac mini&lt;/a>, I’m very, very impressed with it. It’s really a very fast machine — faster than my new iBook.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are the Xbench scores of my &lt;a href="http://ladd.dyndns.org/xbench/merge.xhtml?doc2=113999">Mac mini 1.42Ghz&lt;/a> versus my &lt;a href="http://ladd.dyndns.org/xbench/merge.xhtml?doc2=114000">G4/500 RAID server&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that this is &lt;strong>after&lt;/strong> adding RAM. Before the RAM upgrade, the Mac mini was so horribly slow that I wanted to set it on fire. ProTip: max the RAM.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cobb County Goes Mac</title><link>/archives/1702/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1702/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2005/may/02cobb.html">Apple to Supply iBooks for Cobb County&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Apple???? today announced that the Cobb County School District has selected Apple as its supplier in the largest ever one-to-one computer learning initiative. The district’s program, named “Power To Learn,” plans for Apple to provide iBook???? G4s to every student and teacher in the district, starting with deployment this fall of more than 17,000 iBooks for teachers district-wide and students at four high schools designated as demonstration sites. Pending school board approval, the second and third phases of the program will equip all Cobb County high school and middle school students with iBooks beginning in 2006, resulting in a total deployment of 63,000 iBooks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tiger</title><link>/archives/1700/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1700/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://homepage.mac.com/unxmaal/PhotoAlbum5.html">This&lt;/a> is how &lt;strong>not&lt;/strong> to install Tiger on an older G4:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Insert DVD.&lt;br>
Listen to DVD whir.&lt;br>
Realize you only have a CDRW installed, not a DVDR.&lt;br>
Mutter obscenities.&lt;br>
Re-visit the horror of installing the CDRW into the G4.&lt;br>
Locate old slot-load DVD-Rom drive.&lt;br>
Crack the G4 case and splice in the DVD-R.&lt;br>
Install Tiger, and be amazed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Colorized Mac Minis</title><link>/archives/1671/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1671/</guid><description>&lt;p>These &lt;a href="http://www.123macmini.com/news/story/24.html">colorized&lt;/a> Mac Minis look pretty sweet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is “colorized” really a word?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OSX Comic Book Viewers</title><link>/archives/1668/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1668/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve only found two comic book viewers — apps that will display compressed, scanned comic books — for OSX:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://gumby.misplacedmac.com/">CB Viewer&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://jomic.sourceforge.net/">Jomic&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jomic is large, slow, and Java-based [which you should have guessed from the prior description]. It doesn’t support gradiated image zoom (that I could find), so you can only view images at either full-size or fit-to-window, which is bad when you’re trying to read comic books on a smaller laptop screen.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mac mini Parasite</title><link>/archives/1667/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1667/</guid><description>&lt;p>It warms my technophilic heart to see this &lt;a href="http://www.nodrm.com/index.php?p=104">Mac mini&lt;/a> leeched to the back of a large plasma screen, quietly injecting Apple-ness into the display.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dave Watanabe Is An Idiot</title><link>/archives/1665/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1665/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m revoking my &lt;a href="http://unxmaal.com/wordpress/index.php?p=995">previous statement&lt;/a> about how wonderful and cool NewsFire is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As it turns out, NewsFire’s developer, Dave Watanabe, has decided to start charging $20 for it. My problems with this are many:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>NewsFire really isn’t worth $20. It’s an RSS reader. My toilet has an RSS reader, these days. It might be worth $5.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>There was never any indication that NewsFire was going to be shareware. There was just a prompt to upgrade, and a minor mention of a “registration” system in the release notes.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>There’s no real improvement over the existing, working 0.62 version.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://ranchero.com/netnewswire/beta.php">NetNewsWire Lite&lt;/a> does the same thing, and is free.
I’m not sure which drugs Mr. Watanabe is on. Gone are the days where a developer can give a marginally-better-than-the-competition application away for free, then arbitrarily decide to start charging for the next version. Particularly when Tiger’s version of Safari will support RSS feeds natively within a few months.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>OSX DVD UOP</title><link>/archives/1662/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1662/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hooray for TLAs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="http://xvi.rpc1.org/playerpatch.html">Mac OSX DVD Player User Operations Prohibition&lt;/a> patch allows the user to perform actions that a DVD may regard as ‘prohibited’, such as skipping the ten thousand advertisements for whatever mindless drivel is being pumped out by Disney this month.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I haven’t tried it, so if you do, let me know if it melts your Mac.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iBook Screen Spanning</title><link>/archives/1651/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1651/</guid><description>&lt;p>One nice feature that the Powerbook has over the iBook is support for screen spanning: you can connect an external monitor to the laptop and ‘extend’ the desktop to the new monitor. For some inexplicable reason (save maybe another ‘selling point’ of the Powerbook), iBooks don’t ship with this feature. Instead, they only support screen ‘mirroring’, which is pretty worthless since the laptop goes to sleep with the lid closed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>phpMyAdmin and MySQL on OSX</title><link>/archives/1650/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1650/</guid><description>&lt;p>Macservers.org has a nice &lt;a href="http://www.macservers.org/feature-1.html">article&lt;/a> on how to configure the built-in &lt;a href="http://apache.org">Apache&lt;/a> webserver, and how to install and configure &lt;a href="http://www.macservers.org/feature-2.html">MySQL&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.phpmyadmin.net/">phpMyAdmin&lt;/a> on OSX.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some of the information in the Macservers article is out of date. I recommend getting the updated Mac OSX PHP 5.0 installer package from &lt;a href="http://www.entropy.ch/software/macosx/php/">here&lt;/a>. The newest &lt;a href="http://dev.mysql.com/downloads/mysql/4.0.html">MySQL&lt;/a> package includes an installer for the OSX startup item script, so you won’t need to install the Entropy.ch one.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Entourage and Winmail.dat</title><link>/archives/1646/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1646/</guid><description>&lt;p>In certain cases, some Microsoft mail clients will encode mail attachments as a MIME type of “application/ms-tnef”. These attachments show up as ‘winmail.dat’, and are invariably unusable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.joshjacob.com/macdev/tnef/">TNEF’s Enough&lt;/a> is a free app that extracts files from TNEF stream files, which is pretty handy for Mac users in Windows office environments.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Delicious Library</title><link>/archives/1007/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1007/</guid><description>&lt;p>Delicious Monster’s &lt;a href="http://delicious-monster.com/">Delicious Library&lt;/a> app is supposed to be released today, and I’ve been counting down the minutes. What does this app do?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What doesn’t it do?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Delicious Library’s digital shelves act as a visual card-catalog of your books, movies, music and video games.” It’ll scan in these items using your Apple iSight camera to read the bar code. No, really.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course, it has all the other good stuff you’d expect from a library-type app, including voice-activated catalog searches, iPod-synced catalog lists, user ratings, and recommendations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Favorite OSX Apps</title><link>/archives/1002/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1002/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here’s a list of my favorite OSX apps.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Web: Safari — I’m a Safari fanatic, and really only for its speed and its synced bookmarks.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>IM: &lt;a href="http://adiumx.com">Adium&lt;/a> — I’m a sucker for tabbed interfaces, and this slick, tabbed, multi-protocol chat app is the best around.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.newsfirerss.com/">NewsFire&lt;/a> — As I’m sure you’ve read, Newsfire rox my pants. I’ve tried others, and I still think it’s the best.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Address Book.app — this is an indespensible app for me, especially combined with Quicksilver.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Eliminate iTunes’ Stutter</title><link>/archives/997/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/997/</guid><description>&lt;p>iTunes stutters. Y-Yu-Y-You heard me. It didn’t always do this, though. When I first ran iTunes on my PC, it was a wondrous revelation… but recently, probably after a software update, it developed a stutter. I got fed up tonight and searched until I found the answer buried in an Apple messageboard, away from Google’s prying eyes. The culprit: DirectSound.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, Apple is now using Microsoft’s pitiful DirectSound via QuickTime to play iTunes music. I don’t know if it’s always been this way (I don’t think so), but the way to remedy the stutter is to close iTunes, open QuickTime preferences, and change the ‘Sound Out’ from DirectSound to something more reasonable, like ‘Wave Out.’ Close QuickTime Preferences, open iTunes, and poof! Stutter banished.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More OSX goodies</title><link>/archives/996/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/996/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://projects.tynsoe.org/en/geektool/" title="Tynsoe projects">GeekTool&lt;/a> is a nice little prefpane applet that lets you display time-refreshed unix command outputs or Internet-based images on your desktop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.ragingmenace.com/software/menumeters/">MenuMeters&lt;/a> is a great set of system monitoring tools for OSX, displaying CPU, network, and disk utilization in the top menu bar. Sadly, menu real estate is pretty small on my iBook, so I only use it on my G4.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I tried out Bloglines with the &lt;a href="http://bloglines.com/about/notifier#mac">OSX notifier&lt;/a>, and was less than impressed. I like the persistency of a web-based aggregator, but I hate pretty much everything else. Bloglines doesn’t support importing from OPML, which makes setup a pain, and browsing via a standalone app like NewsFire is much faster [especially if you use keyboard shortcuts].&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>NewsFire</title><link>/archives/995/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/995/</guid><description>&lt;p>Wow! Holy crap! In a hat!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve been using NetNewsWire Lite for reading RSS feeds for the last several months [and if you don’t use a RSS feed-reader, please crawl out from under your rock and smell the sunlight] and though I’ve had no real problems with the application, I’ve not looked for other RSS readers either.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, though, I discovered &lt;a href="http://www.newsfirerss.com/" title="NewsFire. Mac RSS with Style.">NewsFire&lt;/a>. Holy crap, this thing is cool. The UI is very slick and very easy to use, with good, intuitive keyboard shortcuts, and the whole app is very integrated into the OS. You can easily import your old RSS bookmarks, and you can instruct the app to “discover feeds” for a given site, or even the site currently displayed in Safari.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Synergy for OSX</title><link>/archives/993/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/993/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://synergy2.sourceforge.net/" title="Synergy">Synergy&lt;/a> truly rocks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a while now I’ve been using &lt;a href="http://www.opendarwin.org/projects/osx2x/">osx2x&lt;/a> along with &lt;a href="http://ultravnc.sourceforge.net/">UltraVNC&lt;/a>, just so that I could use one keyboard and dual monitors on two computers — a Mac and a PC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>osx2x’s problems were many: the PC would detect a / as a ?, and vice versa; the number pad wouldn’t work, and sometimes the shift key would get stuck. Worse, it was impossible to play games on the PC and span over to the Mac’s monitor — osx2x would either completely garble the mouse commands, or would just crash. I had to put a KVM in place just so that I could switch the hardware keyboard to the PC when I wanted to game.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>WPA + FreeRadius + OSX</title><link>/archives/991/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/991/</guid><description>&lt;p>In a fit of masochism, I decided to secure my Airport Express WLAN via WPA and Radius authentication.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>RADIUS authentication lets you manage access to your wireless LAN from a central RADIUS server, making it much more secure than storing authentication info on your wireless access points.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I picked up a pre-compiled OSX package of &lt;a href="http://www.freeradius.org/">FreeRadius&lt;/a> from &amp;lt;a href=http://carpestellarem.com/Products/StellarRADIUSLite.php&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Carpe Stellarem&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a few other ways to get FreeRadius, including via &lt;a href="http://fink.sourceforge.net/">Fink package&lt;/a>, and by &lt;a href="http://homepage.mac.com/andreaswolf/public/freeradius_installer.html">Andreas Wolf’s installer&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Apple Gives Credit</title><link>/archives/990/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/990/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m sure this is old news [I’m finding articles as old as 2002] but in reading the info for Apple’s latest &lt;a href="http://docs.info.apple.com/article.html?artnum=61798" title="Security Updates">Security Update&lt;/a>, I noticed that in most of the security fixes, Apple gives the discoverer credit for finding and reporting the problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s a lot nicer than suing the whistleblower.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iPod 3.0</title><link>/archives/986/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/986/</guid><description>&lt;p>For my birthday [which isn’t until next week, so you still have &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/registry/registry.html/102-5902498-3150556?%5Fencoding=UTF8&amp;amp;id=1KW8KHS424080">time&lt;/a>], I traded my 3rd Gen iPod to &lt;a href="http://unxmaal.com/cgi-bin/clickcount.cgi?action=jump&amp;amp;URL=http://networkgeek.org">Daniel&lt;/a>, and got myself a new &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/ipod/" title="Apple - iPod">20GB 4th Generation iPod&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stanford XGrid</title><link>/archives/984/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/984/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve set up my G4/500 to take part in the &lt;a href="http://cmgm.stanford.edu/~cparnot/xgrid-stanford/index.html" title="XGrid@Stanford">XGrid@Stanford&lt;/a> project. By installing and running Apple’s &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/acg/xgrid/">XGrid&lt;/a> client, you can donate CPU cycles to this project. Currently the project only has about 150 Macs, running at a total of &lt;a href="http://cmgm.stanford.edu/~cparnot/xgrid-stanford/gauge/gauge.html">123Ghz&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No floppy drive on my mac? No problem!</title><link>/archives/982/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/982/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today I was going through old floppy diskettes and found one that had some documents that needed to be archived in a more accessible format than 1.44M floppies. Unfortunately, it was from my PowerMac 7500 days (OS9 at best), and my OSX PowerBook doesn’t have a floppy. There’s all sorts of nasty software you can install on a windows box, but I needed a simple, one-off solution to get the files off the disk, without needing to reboot on a live linux CD image or anything wacky like that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Apple Stores</title><link>/archives/981/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/981/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here’s &lt;a href="http://www.ifoapplestore.com/the_stores.html" title="ifo Apple Store - The Stores">everything&lt;/a> you could possibly want to know about &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/retail/">Apple retail stores&lt;/a> — and then some.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iPod Infrared Remote</title><link>/archives/978/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/978/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here’s how to turn your iPod into a &lt;a href="http://features.engadget.com/entry/6336778455600767/" title="How-To Turn your iPod in to a Universal Infrared Remote Control">Universal Infrared Remote Control&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Safari MT Bookmarklets</title><link>/archives/974/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/974/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m terribly lame for only having discovered this &lt;em>now&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here’s how to &lt;a href="http://www.antipixel.com/blog/archives/2003/01/24/help_with_bookmarklets.html#chris_001536" title="Antipixel | Blog | Help with Bookmarklets">fix MoveableType’s Bookmarklets in Safari&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Locking the screen in OSX</title><link>/archives/964/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/964/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve been using a Fedora workstation in conjuction with my iBook at work, and I’ve gotten used to the handy ‘lock screen’ button on the Gnome toolbar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wanted the same type of ‘lock screen’ button for OSX, but didn’t know of any quick and easy way to enable it. I did some research, and came up with this nice [but oddly hidden] method:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Keychain Access is used to store passwords to web sites, network servers, and lockable volumes. However, it also provides a quick way of securing your computer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obsessive iTunes Post</title><link>/archives/959/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/959/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yes! &lt;a href="http://apple.com">Apple&lt;/a> just released &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/itunes/download/">iTunes 4.5&lt;/a>, which includes a lot of new features, the most important [to me] being the ability to make Smart Playlists that include other Smart Playlists.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I’ve been doing lately is creating two playlists: “Top 4GB of songs, rated 3 or higher, not played in 2 weeks, sorted by rating”, and “Danger!!”, which is 2GB of completely random stuff [and in a library of 18000 songs or more, it’s really dangerous].&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Firestarter FX</title><link>/archives/937/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/937/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://unxmaal.com/cgi-bin/clickcount.cgi?action=jump&amp;amp;URL=http://samarnold.net" title="The world's biggest ex-soccer player">Sam&lt;/a> introduced me to &lt;a href="http://www.projectomega.org/subcat.php?lg=en&amp;amp;php=products_firestarter">Firestarter FX&lt;/a>, which is a nice little CD-burning app for OSX.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It supports the following features:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Backs up CDs that neither Apple’s Disc-Copy nor Roxio Toast can backup.&lt;br>
iso and cue/bin support.&lt;br>
Overburning.&lt;br>
iso and cue/bin image creation.&lt;br>
2-click folder backup.&lt;br>
2-click CDRW erase.&lt;br>
Simulation.&lt;br>
Customizable RAM cache.&lt;br>
High speed burning.&lt;br>
Buffer under-run technology.&lt;br>
Multi-session burning.&lt;br>
Paranoia audio-cd ripping, for best error protection copy.&lt;br>
CDDB access to automatically create CD-TEXT data.&lt;br>
CD-TEXT reading and writing with drives that support it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Red Pill</title><link>/archives/930/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/930/</guid><description>&lt;p>My Matrix screen saver — &lt;a href="http://meta.ath0.com/software/redpill/">Red Pill&lt;/a> — kicks your Matrix screen saver’s ass.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Geek post. Flee.</title><link>/archives/918/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/918/</guid><description>&lt;p>Over the weekend, I upgraded my G4 to Panther. I’ve been pretty nervous about doing so, because there were a few things wrong with the existing Jaguar install. The G4 acts as my main fileserver, with 160GB of storage in a mirrored RAID, so it’s pretty important that it didn’t crash and burn during an upgrade.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I got a 120GB drive from &lt;a href="http://tech-ees.com/" title="Yes James, it's more expensive than Newegg. Shut up already.">Tech-EE’s&lt;/a> and crammed it into the G4’s case. With 3 drives, I’ve still got room for 3 more, though I’m not sure the power supply can handle that many, considering the main drive is a Quantum Fireball 18GB SCSI LVD 15,000rpm drive.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>/archives/914/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/914/</guid><description>&lt;p>Per this &lt;a href="http://arstechnica.infopop.net/OpenTopic/page?a=tpc&amp;amp;s=50009562&amp;amp;f=8300945231&amp;amp;m=9900929295">ArsMac thread&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://apple.com/macosx/">Panther&lt;/a> features “Hot-File-Adaptive-Clustering”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In plainer terms, the OS defragments HFS+ filesystems automatically, if the files being used are smaller than 20MB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Be sure to read the thread, for it contains nifty snippets of the actual kernel code, since the core OS, &lt;a href="http://developer.apple.com/darwin/">Darwin&lt;/a>, is Open Source.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yeah, if you’ve been living in a cave or something and haven’t already had some Mac fanatic splatter drool on you about it already, &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/expose/">Expos??&lt;/a> really does &lt;em>rock&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iTunes is free software</title><link>/archives/910/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/910/</guid><description>&lt;p>Windows users, listen up:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/itunes/">iTunes&lt;/a> for Windows is &lt;strong>free&lt;/strong>. It doesn’t cost anything. It will play your existing MP3 files just fine. It will rip your CDs just fine, and you still don’t have to pay a dime to Apple. It’ll keep your MP3s organized, and you &lt;em>still don’t have to pay any money to anyone&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It can also show trippy visual effects when you play your MP3s, and yeah, those effects are free, too.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Window Shade X</title><link>/archives/895/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/895/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve been playing with &lt;a href="http://unsanity.com">Unsanity&lt;/a>‘s &lt;a href="http://unsanity.com/haxies/wsx/">Window Shade X&lt;/a> public preview. One of the nice new features of version 3 is “Minimize In Place”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Suggestion for WSX3:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIPed windows should [do something] when their dock icon is clicked. Right now I can’t decide what that something is; I think that perhaps a double-click should maximize all of them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MIP iTunes, and open Safari. Now, consider your mouse movements. In order to maximize the MIPed iTunes, if the Safari window hides the iTunes MIP, you must first either cmd-tab to iTunes or click the icon, then click the MIPed window. Thus your mouse at worst travels from the center of the screen to the bottom of the screen, then almost to another edge of the screen, just to maximize a MIPed window.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>NuBus Linux</title><link>/archives/887/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/887/</guid><description>&lt;p>It looks like it’s possible [but not easy] to install &lt;a href="http://nubus.tuxppc.org/plain_page.php?caller=powermaclinux.php3+record=77">Linux&lt;/a> on my old &lt;a href="http://everymac.com/systems/apple/powermac/stats/powermac_6100_66.html">6100/33 Power Mac&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Though I’m not really sure why I’d &lt;em>want&lt;/em> to.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Printing from WinXP to OSX</title><link>/archives/880/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/880/</guid><description>&lt;p>After hours of banging on it, I finally figured out how to enable printing via SMB from a Windows XP machine to a Mac OSX machine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You’d think that with a Mac it’d be a point-and-click deal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Think again. “Think different.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Refer to &lt;a href="http://homepage.mac.com/william_white/print_to_samba.html">William White’s guide&lt;/a> for a detailed list.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The steps, in my particular case, are as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Download and install the &lt;a href="http://gimp-print.sourceforge.net/MacOSX.php3">Gimp-Print&lt;/a> drivers. This step is pretty straightforward, although you may need to install the ESP Ghostscript drivers too.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New Powermacs</title><link>/archives/873/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/873/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m drooling over the new &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/powermac/">G5 Powermacs&lt;/a>. $2999 for a dual 2Ghz 64-bit platform isn’t that outrageous, either, considering that &lt;a href="http://www.sun.com">Sun&lt;/a>‘s dual 1.2Ghz 64-bit system &lt;a href="http://store.sun.com/catalog/doc/BrowsePage.jhtml?cid=77642">starts&lt;/a> at around $13,995.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Army goes OSX</title><link>/archives/870/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/870/</guid><description>&lt;p>According to this &lt;a href="http://news.netcraft.com/archives/2003/06/10/recent_changes_at_notable_sites.html">Netcraft&lt;/a> article, the Army has moved their &lt;a href="http://www.army.mil">www.army.mil&lt;/a> server to &lt;a href="http://apple.com/macosx">Mac OSX&lt;/a>, the first OS transition for that server since 1999.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The article also points out that Apple has switched its Knowledge Base servers to &lt;a href="http://wwws.sun.com/software/solaris/index.html">Solaris&lt;/a>. Other anecdotal evidence shows that Apple is performing load-balancing between Solaris and OSX servers, possible for internal investigation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>XShelf</title><link>/archives/860/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/860/</guid><description>&lt;p>A common irritation for me, while moving files from one folder to another, is having to stop the move in order to open another Finder window. Springloaded folders help a bit, but not much, and only for immediate transfers. They don’t help at all for moving files to a folder that hasn’t been created yet –“woops, I forgot to make that folder!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That said, &lt;a href="http://homepage.mac.com/khsu/XShelf/XShelf.html">XShelf&lt;/a> is freaking awesome. Go get it now.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iPod Batteries</title><link>/archives/856/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/856/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you’re one of the unlucky few who’ve had problems with your iPod battery, you can buy a replacement iPod battery from &lt;a href="http://www.ipodbattery.com/" title="How obvious a domain name could they get?">iPodBattery.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://unxmaal.com/cgi-bin/clickcount.cgi?action=jump&amp;amp;URL=http://abracapocus.org/" title="This should make her Blogshares valuation go up!">Laura&lt;/a> had some weird problems with her iPod. For some reason iTunes wouldn’t update the play count of songs that she’d listened to after she installed the newest iPod software. I wiped and reinstalled the software, and now it works fine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RSS Aggregators</title><link>/archives/851/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/851/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve been playing with &lt;a href="http://ranchero.com/netnewswire/">NetNewsWire&lt;/a>, an RSS news aggregator for OSX. This is the first news aggregator I’ve used, and I’m very impressed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A news aggregator is an application that downloads information from multiple sites, usually in the form of an RSS feed. The information is normally news, or weblog posts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A very cool feature of NetNewsWire is that it periodically checks the feeds to which you’ve subscribed, and if it finds something new, it will download the headline and notify you.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>