<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Diary on</title><link>/categories/diary/</link><description>Recent content in Diary on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/diary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>League of Evil Geniuses</title><link>/archives/1800/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1800/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m now the proud wearer of this awesome &lt;a href="http://www.pegasuspublishing.com/xcart/product.php?productid=26704&amp;amp;cat=263&amp;amp;page=2">shirt&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pegasus Publishing rocks. Go buy stuff from them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Key West</title><link>/archives/1755/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1755/</guid><description>&lt;p>Woot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m in Key West.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And you’re not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Of course, wherever you are, you’re probably with my baggage.)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ikea Madness</title><link>/archives/1719/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1719/</guid><description>&lt;p>Heather and I donned battle armor and braved the new &lt;a href="http://ikea.com">Ikea&lt;/a>store on Monday morning. The store is like an enormous theme park for trendy-but-thrifty adults, complete with a neato magnetic-locking freight escalator as a ‘ride’. I could’ve blown a lot more money than I did, but I managed to escape with only a TV stand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;a href="http://www.ikea.com/webapp/wcs/stores/servlet/ProductDisplay?catalogId=10101&amp;amp;storeId=12&amp;amp;langId=-1&amp;amp;productId=51511">link&lt;/a>] to Mark????r TV stand&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uvalde, TX</title><link>/archives/1711/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1711/</guid><description>&lt;p>Posting from vacation hot-spot (literally), &lt;a href="http://www.uvaldeleadernews.com/">Uvalde&lt;/a>, TX.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We drove for about 18 hours. I’m going to bed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tomorrow’s for rafting and hiking and looking at dinosaur tracks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>VNV Nation</title><link>/archives/1706/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1706/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="http://vnvnation.com">VNV Nation&lt;/a> show was spectacular.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll post more later. Now I must fall over.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Doug Visniski</title><link>/archives/1654/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1654/</guid><description>&lt;p>My friend and mentor, &lt;a href="http://phatss.com">Doug Visniski&lt;/a>, passed away this weekend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Doug got me my first job in Atlanta, and was my shift lead in Sprint’s IBO NOC. He had an insane amount of knowledge about networking tucked in his head, and even more knowledge about automobile mechanics. He was the only guy I knew who could remotely troubleshoot obscure physical-layer issues while putting together engine parts at his desk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He taught me a great deal about deep physical-layer troubleshooting, and was instrumental in maintaining the outstanding quality of service provided by the Sprint backbone during his many years with the company.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Misadventures in Printing</title><link>/archives/983/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/983/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week I went to Birmingham and set up my sister’s home wireless LAN. She’s only now gotten her very first computer, which is a 14″ G4 iBook. She’s already complained about “all the porn on the Internet”, and she’s sent her first dirty email Forward.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m so proud.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’d decided to hand-me-down my old Linksys 802.11b access point to her, but when I set it up at her house, it promptly died. This involved much obscenity, and a few trips to &lt;a href="http://www.radioshack.com/">Radio Trash&lt;/a>. She ended up with a nice Linksys 802.11g AP/Router, and I had none.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spiderman 2</title><link>/archives/969/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/969/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://spiderman.sonypictures.com/">Spiderman 2&lt;/a> rocks. Go see it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh wait, you’ll all have to wait for 24 more hours! Sorry!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Defective Dog</title><link>/archives/967/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/967/</guid><description>&lt;p>Somewhere in the twisted mental pathways that make up the tiny brain of my little dog, &lt;a href="http://unxmaal.com/gallery/puppy%21">Tak&lt;/a>, the phrase “It’s a trap!” — said in an &lt;a href="http://images.google.com/images?q=admiral%20ackbar&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;lr=&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;amp;safe=off&amp;amp;sa=N&amp;amp;tab=wi">Admiral Ackbar&lt;/a> voice — means “there is a squirrel outside. Go find and kill it now!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Really.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“It’s a trap!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the dog bolts out of the room, off the porch, and over to the nearest tree, hell-bent for some squealy squirrel death.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>HP&amp;TPOA</title><link>/archives/963/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/963/</guid><description>&lt;p>Because Laura is special, she scored some sneak preview passes to &lt;a href="http://imdb.com/title/tt0304141/">Harry Potter and The Prisoner of Azkaban&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Not really spoilers, but just in case.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Burger King Incident</title><link>/archives/962/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/962/</guid><description>&lt;p>Due to a bad dining decision, I went to lunch at Burger King last week. As I moved through the line, I noticed a slightly overweight Hispanic girl leaning against the counter, waiting for her food. She was wearing low-cut hip-hugger jeans.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here’s my Fashion Hint for the month:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are a girl, and you have a .. hair problem.. don’t wear low-cut jeans. Most importantly, if you are a girl and you have thick glossy ass-hair, ass-hair that has crawled out of your ass and up your spine to reach your mid-back in some unholy ass-hair creeper-vine fashion, ass-hair that would be more fitting on a swarthy Italian sailor’s chest [or head], please, &lt;em>please&lt;/em>, for the love of all that is holy, &lt;strong>please do not wear low-cut jeans when you have an ass-pelt!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hooray for Home Ownership</title><link>/archives/961/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/961/</guid><description>&lt;p>Week before last, the AC went out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For those of you not living in Atlanta: this is a crisis of Biblical proportions. Even in April.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I called around, on a Sunday, and A Guy to come out and look at it. He mumbled something about leaks, and about the age of the AC unit, filled it with coolant, charged me $180 and left.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Three days later, the AC was again blowing tepid air.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More MINI Madness</title><link>/archives/955/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/955/</guid><description>&lt;p>My third-day impressions about the MINI:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll preface by saying that my trade-in was a 2000 Ford Escort ZX2&lt;br>
automatic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot of people have complained that the MINI is too loud for long trips, that the ride is too rough, especially on run-flats, and so on. I haven’t noticed any of that, probably because my senses were dulled by four years of Ford Escort. possibly not, though, because Laura noted how quiet it was inside the car with the windows up. Bumps that were very jarring in the Escort are still noticeable in the MINI, but only on an ‘informational’ level — it doesn’t feel like serious structural damage is taking place when I drive over a small pothole.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MINI</title><link>/archives/953/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/953/</guid><description>&lt;center>
 &lt;br /> &lt;a href="http://unxmaal.com/gallery/album07/mini_first_pic">&lt;img src=http://unxmaal.com/albums/album07/mini_first_pic.thumb.jpg width=150 height=128 border=0>&lt;/a>&lt;/a>&lt;/p> 
 &lt;p>
 Oh yes, it is mine now.
 &lt;/p>
 &lt;p>
 I&amp;#8217;m gonna go sleep in it.
 &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I am not obsessed.</title><link>/archives/950/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/950/</guid><description>&lt;p>Given the VIN of an ordered MINI Cooper, you can paste it into the Wallenius Wilhelmsen &lt;a href="http://213.31.205.37/GLWebApps.AppTracking">cargo tracking page&lt;/a> and locate the name of the ship that carries said MINI, as well as estimated departure and arrival dates.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It shows that the vessel containing my MINI, the Curitiba, has sailed, and is due to arrive in Charleston, SC on 3-30. This could change, because the shipping terminal info is a little hedgy until the ship proves to be underway.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MINI</title><link>/archives/947/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/947/</guid><description>&lt;p>After years(!) of drooling, I ordered a &lt;a href="http://miniusa.com">MINI Cooper S&lt;/a> from &lt;a href="http://www.atlantamini.com">Global Imports&lt;/a>. &lt;em>I would’ve gone to Hank Aaron Mini, but the sales weasels tried to rob me. Luckily, I know Excel and wouldn’t put up with them trying to charge interest on the total amount, without counting the down payment.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s Chili Red with black stripes, roof, and mirrors, similar to &lt;a href="http://www.sjbaker.org/telamom/colours/cr_b_b.jpg">this one&lt;/a>. It should arrive sometime in May.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MINI Links&lt;/p>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://mini2.com">Mini2&lt;/a> has great forums.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.motoringfile.com/">MotoringFile&lt;/a> is an excellent MINI weblog.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://eal.us">Eric Longman&lt;/a>‘s weblog. He helped out with some of my MINI questions.&lt;/ul>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Beaver</title><link>/archives/942/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/942/</guid><description>&lt;center>
 &lt;a href="http://unxmaal.com/gallery/friends/beaver">&lt;img src=http://unxmaal.com/albums/friends/beaver.thumb.jpg width=150 height=124 border=0>&lt;/a>
&lt;/center>
&lt;p>My first girlfriend mailed me a little stuffed hamster/beaver/thing. It was doused in her perfume, ‘to remember her by’, since she lived two hours away and I only got to see her every other weekend.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Twelve years later, I have no idea what became of that girl, and the beaver is now a thoroughly-masticated dog toy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There’s a parable in there somewhere.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Roomba</title><link>/archives/941/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/941/</guid><description>&lt;center>
 &lt;a href="http://unxmaal.com/gallery/922brentwood/roomba">&lt;img src=http://unxmaal.com/albums/922brentwood/roomba.thumb.jpg width=150 height=129 border=0>&lt;/a>
&lt;/center>
&lt;p>Because &lt;a href="http://unxmaal.com/cgi-bin/clickcount.cgi?action=jump&amp;amp;URL=http://abracapocus.org/">Laura&lt;/a>‘s the best girlfriend ever, she got me a &lt;a href="http://roombavac.com">Roomba&lt;/a> for Christmas. It took a while to get here, and I wanted to test it for a while before writing a glowing review.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In short, the Roomba sucks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that’s exactly what it’s supposed to do. It sucks without my intervention, except a few times when it got stuck or trapped, and it does a damn fine job of sucking. It sucks up cat hair, cat litter, cat feces, cat barf, cat dandruff, and all the other various parts of cat that are strewn around my house. It sucks up sand-dune sized litter drifts without a complaint, and it sweeps up the gnawed corpses of toilet paper rolls left by the dog. It handles 2/3 of the floorspace of my house in about an hour, and has some battery charge left over.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tropical Pooping Paradise</title><link>/archives/934/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/934/</guid><description>&lt;center>
 &lt;a href="http://unxmaal.com/gallery/922brentwood/IMG_0048">&lt;img src=http://unxmaal.com/albums/922brentwood/IMG_0048.thumb.jpg width=113 height=150 border=0>&lt;/a>
&lt;/center>
&lt;p>A while back, I suggested we paint the bathroom &lt;font color=green>green&lt;/font>, because anything would’ve been better than the nasty, soul-sucking &lt;a href="http://unxmaal.com/gallery/922brentwood/aaf" title="It's really nasty, even though you can't tell in this bad picture.">blue-grey&lt;/a> that the bathroom had been painted in since the early 70s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the time, I was joking, but I think it turned out &lt;a href="http://unxmaal.com/gallery/922brentwood/IMG_0047">quite nicely&lt;/a>. I want to continue the Tiki theme, adding a bamboo print border, and eventually replacing the toilet and bathtub with rattan replicas. Within a few years, perhaps I can make defecating in my bathroom a truly tropical experience, replete with strange diseases and mysterious insects eager to inflict and explore supporating wounds.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Obligatory San Francisco Vacation Pix</title><link>/archives/924/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/924/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here’s the &lt;a href="http://unxmaal.com/gallery/album05">Gallery&lt;/a>, folks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pep Drones</title><link>/archives/904/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/904/</guid><description>&lt;p>Needing tires, we stopped at &lt;a href="http://www.pepboys.com">Pep-Boys&lt;/a> on Cobb Parkway. We went in through the service entrance, and stood in line for ten minutes. When we finally got to the counter, the desk clerk said, “We can’t do tires here. You have to go into the store and go all the way to the back.” Great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We went to the back of the store, and waited at the counter for several minutes. An employee saw us and said, “You’re here for tires? You can’t get tires here. You have to go to that counter over there.” So we walked to the next counter. And waited. A few minutes later, a guy who had been chatting with one of one of the employees noticed us standing at the counter, and nudged the employee. The employee, “Jon”, came over to the desk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Birthday</title><link>/archives/896/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/896/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s my birthday, so gimme loot!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And by the way, &lt;a href="http://unxmaal.com/cgi-bin/clickcount.cgi?action=jump&amp;amp;URL=http://abracapocus.org/">Laura&lt;/a> is the best girlfriend ever, because she got me an &lt;a href="http://store.apple.com/1-800-MY-APPLE/WebObjects/AppleStore?productLearnMore=M9130G/A">iPod Dock&lt;/a>, a sock monkey, a Hawaiian shirt, and a Tiki Head!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mold</title><link>/archives/894/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/894/</guid><description>&lt;p>Saturday, &lt;a href="http://unxmaal.com/cgi-bin/clickcount.cgi?action=jump&amp;amp;URL=http://abracapocus.org/">Laura&lt;/a> told me we had mold in the hallway. Even though I wanted to keep it for a pet [“Sparky! Play dead! Now make penicillin!”], she said we had to get rid of it. My response was “I have no idea how to get rid of mold.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is why I have parents, I guess. And &lt;a href="http://google.com">Google&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Upon the recommendation of Mom and Uncle Google, we had to do several things to remove the mold, and to keep it from coming back. First, as the mold was on the ceiling and the upper parts of the walls in the hallway, Laura had to scrubbed the area with bleach water. Next, we’re leaving a light on in the hallway.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Food</title><link>/archives/886/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/886/</guid><description>&lt;p>Parenthetically, isn’t it great being a slob AND being forgetful at the same time? It’s always a pleasant surprise when you look down and find some spare food. “Hey look! A piece of pepperoni I missed! And since it’s on my man-teat and not the floor, it’s perfectly edible!!”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tree</title><link>/archives/883/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/883/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s always lovely to be interrupted from one’s afternoon net-browsing by the sounds of tornadic wind and the cracking of &lt;a href="http://unxmaal.com/gallery/922brentwood/abi">tree-trunks&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once the wind had died down, I went outside to find one of my ancient oaks broken off a few feet up its &lt;a href="http://unxmaal.com/gallery/922brentwood/abq">trunk&lt;/a>, sprawled across a good portion of my back yard. It’s a good thing that &lt;a href="http://unxmaal.com/gallery/922brentwood/abp">shed&lt;/a> was there to break the fall.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A week later, and I’ve got insurance checks in hand, and am waiting for the Scary Tree Cutting Guy™ and the Confederate Rebel Contractor Guy™ to show up and start removing tree and shed bits.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pocket Pool</title><link>/archives/875/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/875/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week, my swimming pool had become a deep green, indistinguishable from the color of the murky waters of the Chattahoochee, so I decided to invest in some more pool chemicals. I went to the pool supply store, blew $120 on chemicals, and when I got home, I found that my ancient pool pump had finally died.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://unxmaal.com/cgi-bin/clickcount.cgi?action=jump&amp;amp;URL=http://networkgeek.org">Daniel&lt;/a> and I worked for most of the weekend on the pump, first removing it, then replacing it with a new, much more expensive, pump. The lady at the pool supply store was shocked and awed by the old pump, as it was so outdated that she could find no reference in her supply manual.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Security+</title><link>/archives/862/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/862/</guid><description>&lt;p>After several weeks of study [many more than it should’ve taken], I took the &lt;a href="http://www.comptia.org/certification/security/">CompTIA Security+&lt;/a> Exam, and aced it with a score of 820/900.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I spent about three weeks longer to prepare for the exam than was really necessary, because I made the terrible mistake of purchasing the &lt;a href="http://www.wiley.com/WileyCDA/WileyTitle/productCd-0764525999.html">Wiley Security+ Prep Guide&lt;/a>. This book is crap. It appears that the authors wrote an “Intro to Security” handbook, realized they couldn’t sell it, and slapped a “Security+ Prep Guide” moniker upon the cover. The book is very poorly organized, with large chunks of the material spread throughout the book and referenced by “See Chapter X”. It does cover about half of the information required for the exam, but that information only takes up a tenth of the book. The rest is filled with useless trivia that is only obliquely referenced in the exam.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Meat Party</title><link>/archives/861/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/861/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last night, geeks congregated at my place to eat meat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a alt="SPACE MEAT" href="http://unxmaal.com/gallery/friends/adb">&lt;img src=http://unxmaal.com/albums/friends/adb.thumb.jpg width=150 height=97 border=0>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laura made the world’s best salsa. Finally, after much coercing, Daniel, Dori, Chris, James, and Robert showed up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The result was to be expected: James repeatedly shot himself in the toe, Robert tried to play with James’ gun, and there was a general argument over whether IPX/SPX sucks more than TCP/IP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The only casualty was an unfortunate [and very ugly] insect.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interview from Hell</title><link>/archives/858/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/858/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today, I experienced the Interview from Hell.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I applied for a job via &lt;a href="http://www.ajcjobs.com/">AJC&lt;/a> yesterday, and an hour later an HR rep for the company called me. She said the interview would take 30 minutes, and to be there at 9 AM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I got there at about 8:45, they herded me and 60 other people into a very small room, and gave us an application to fill out, and a huge test.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Passed the CCNA</title><link>/archives/848/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/848/</guid><description>&lt;p>Woohoo!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I passed the &lt;a href="http://www.cisco.com/warp/public/10/wwtraining/certprog/testing/current_exams/640-607.html">Cisco Certified Network Associate&lt;/a> exam with a score of 913/1000.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This means I can finally &lt;em>stop&lt;/em> studying for the exam.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Matt Rossi’s Book</title><link>/archives/846/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/846/</guid><description>&lt;p>In case you haven’t heard, &lt;a href="http://unxmaal.com/cgi-bin/clickcount.cgi?action=jump&amp;amp;URL=http://ezrael.org/">Matt Rossi&lt;/a>‘s first book, &lt;a href="http://www.monkeybrainbooks.com/Things_That_Never_Were.html">Things That Never Were&lt;/a>, will be released this summer. I’ll post more about it once it’s officially released, and I’m drooling to get my hands on a copy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Congratulations, Matt!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AOL Sucks</title><link>/archives/845/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/845/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yesterday, at about 2:30 PM, my AIM screen name, “unxmaal”, dropped offline. When I tried to reconnect, I got a message saying the account was “suspended.” I tried logging onto &lt;a href="https://www.aim.com">www.aim.com&lt;/a> via the link provided in the message, and found that all the AIM account info pages lead to a dead-end at home.netscape.com.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I called AOL’s billing center, at 1-888-265-8003, and spoke with a rep. According to this person, that screen name was associated with a dialup account I’d cancelled last year. Since the account was cancelled, I could no longer use it for AIM, nor could I create a new AIM account and move the name ‘unxmaal’ to it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Studying</title><link>/archives/842/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/842/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve scheduled my CCNA exam for a couple of weeks from now, so I’ve been studying like a madman.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Normally I’ll get up in the morning, eat breakfast, and go to Starbuck’s, which is now my “office”. I study from about 8AM until 2PM, then go home for lunch. Today, I got done with a chapter early, and after going home for lunch, decided to stay and study.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Me: I decided to stay home this afternoon and study here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unemployed</title><link>/archives/841/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/841/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few hours after I moved the last boxes of junk from my old apartment into my new house, I was laid off from my job as a network engineer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It sucks, but I knew it would happen sooner or later. Sprint had been holding the layoff axe over our heads for over a year and a half, and the latest round of rumors convinced me to really start looking for other employment.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>