<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Story on</title><link>/categories/story/</link><description>Recent content in Story on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/story/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Wegner</title><link>/archives/1935/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1935/</guid><description>&lt;p>There’s decent money to be made in storage auctions. At least, there used to be, before the reality TV shows made everyone think they could get rich quick. The unit was crammed with old boxes and some furniture. The furniture caught my eye — a refinished vintage desk from the fifties or sixties could sell for quite a bit. The crowd was sparse, and I won the auction for a steal. After the auction, I drove the box truck back to my warehouse, and began unloading it. My warehouse was a small prefab metal building with a roll-up garage door that my father had used, when he was alive, to store junk in, and to dream about building race cars. To my knowledge, no car had ever graced the concrete floor of that building.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reclamation</title><link>/archives/1927/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1927/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Posted to Reddit as “I found something while cleaning out a hoarder’s house”&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’d been working reclamation for a little over a year. We called it reclamation, but that’s a euphemism for ‘throwing away crazy people’s shit’. I work for CLK, one of the largest property owners in the Southeast. Chuck L “Chuckles” Langtry bought hundreds of distressed properties for pennies on the dollar during the recession, and built an empire renting them back to the same poor people the banks had just evicted.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Curb Furniture</title><link>/archives/1918/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1918/</guid><description>&lt;p>I ignored Jesse’s 15th text. “This is heavy, you jerk!” I was far less concerned about Jesse’s potential hernia than my position on the leaderboards. The stupid fourteen year old DRDRED43 refused to move away from the turret, and I was getting destroyed. The game stuttered for a moment, and my connection dropped. “Fucking Comcast,” I muttered, and shoved back from my desk. My phone buzzed again. “God dammit, Jesse.” I sighed, shoved my feet into some sandals, and walked out the door.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Battery Room</title><link>/archives/1922/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1922/</guid><description>&lt;p>“Lowest man on the totem pole.” That’s how my boss described it. That’s how I got stuck on night shift. That made me “The New Guy”. Or “TFNG”, as my coworkers said during the two weeks of day shift training I got at the start of the job. I’m a junior network administrator, right out of college, riding on a friend of a friend’s recommendation. I was responsible for making sure everything stayed the same over night — all the little red lights stayed red, and the green lights stayed green. I had very little idea what I was doing, but in government work, the one thing you can count on is that the task is documented somewhere. Usually on paper, in a binder. I’d done PC tech support for a few years during college, but had never worked with network gear before. If my résumé isn’t outright false, it definitely stinks of cheese.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Audra</title><link>/archives/1914/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1914/</guid><description>&lt;p>Audra forgot to lock her laptop that morning. We had been dating for about four years, and living together for three. I was happy, had been happy, and I truly thought everything was fine. She left for her Saturday run in the park, and I stayed behind, content to play video games on my lazy weekend morning. When I went to the kitchen, my cat, which had been sleeping on the laptop keyboard, got up and meowed at me. I noticed then that the screen was unlocked. I pushed the cat out of the way, and sat down, thinking I would ensure the cat hadn’t made a mess of anything. Then I noticed an instant message window. “I love you too!”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Witches and The Circle</title><link>/archives/1906/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1906/</guid><description>&lt;p>My great-aunt had died the year before. Her house was locked up in probate until issues of inheritance were settled. My father was acting as caretaker of the property, which meant I took care of the place while my old man bought booze with my great-aunt’s money. I didn’t mind; it got me out of my place, away from my old man, and it made a nice place to have parties and hang out with my friends. My friend Chris loved the place. I think he also needed a place to hide, somewhere away from his own house with all of his dead mother’s things lying around, right where she left them, before a sleep-deprived truck driver snuffed out her life like a candle on a store-bought birthday cake.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Gap In The Wall</title><link>/archives/1887/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1887/</guid><description>&lt;p>My name is China Westerson. China, like the country, not the dinnerware. I am nearly nineteen, and I am haunted. You might think it strange that I say that I am haunted, instead of saying, perhaps, I live in a haunted house, or I have seen a ghost. There’s a difference. When you’re haunted, it follows you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I grew up in Mobile, Alabama, in my great-uncle John’s ancient Greek Revival, and it was a haunted house. Nothing too impressive; objects would move when you weren’t looking, doors that you had closed on the way out would be open upon returning home. We liked the ghosts of that house. They seemed like family, and according to my great-uncle, a few were. Old houses always have ghosts, he said. They have ghosts just like they have wood rot, plumbing problems, and bad wiring.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Thing On The TV</title><link>/archives/1884/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1884/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I was about thirteen, I stayed at my uncle’s house over the summer. I didn’t know it, but my parents were getting divorced and they wanted me to have a fun summer without dealing with the stress of moving. I loved my uncle’s place, so I was thrilled to find out that I would get to stay there all summer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My uncle’s house was not very pretty, a big old farmhouse with peeling yellow paint, but the farm was amazing. I was from the city, and my house barely had a yard, much less twenty acres of fields and forest, and a creek that ran through it all. At first, my favorite thing to do was to simply run through those fields, as hard as I could, until I was so hot and exhausted I thought I might pass out, then jump into the cool waters of the forest-shaded creek.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Side Tunnel</title><link>/archives/1881/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1881/</guid><description>&lt;p>I hated that town. Sprawled across the rotting foothills of a dead mountain chain, the city was a mass of Old South racism and corruption, filled with inhabitants too poor or too sentimental to leave for someplace better. The city sweltered in the mid-summer heat, smog from traffic mixing with lethal amounts of pollen and dust to form a soup that killed asthmatics as effectively a whiff of mustard gas.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Delivery</title><link>/archives/1876/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1876/</guid><description>&lt;p>I saw him for the first time in the freezer. It was late on a Friday night, really Saturday morning, and I was moving food to the cooler for the morning crew. I pulled a box from the shelf and turned, and there, right there by the door, he was standing. A dark shape — no, a dim shape, fuzzy in those few seconds of vision, my eyes not quite certain if they were focusing on the freezer door or this thing in front of it. Pale arms outstretched and raised towards me. Hollow eyes black against a pallid face, and a mouth that opened as if to speak. I heard the click and slide of tongue on teeth, underneath the low wheeze of the freezer fan. And he was gone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Methenes Chapel</title><link>/archives/1872/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1872/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Goat roared down the dusty country road, shattering the silence of the late October twilight. The Goat was a 1969 Pontiac GTO “Judge”, Ram Air and a Rock Crusher transmission. Jay had painted it a glowing, canary “arrest me” yellow, and he had mounted a goat skull on the dash. “You wanna see Methenes Chapel?” Jay shouted at me over  the roar. “Sure,” I said. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>We were college roommates, both nineteen, weird, into heavy metal, goth, industrial, and false occultism. We both knew our inverted pentagrams were fake, but it surely offended the normals in those small, rural Alabama farming communities. One of our favorite activities was ghost-hunting, which to us meant driving to supposedly haunted locations and acting out our own developmentally-challenged “Beavis and Butthead” episodes. &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Mug</title><link>/archives/1874/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1874/</guid><description>&lt;p>“Whose mug is this?” Becky asked. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>“No idea,” I replied. “What are you talking about?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“This mug right here,” she said. I leaned back in my chair and craned my neck to see. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I’m trying to watch this show,” I said. “What’s the big deal about a mug?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I’ve never seen it before,” Becky said, getting that tone in her voice like I was about to be in trouble.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“So what? You collect cups and mugs like most people … er, don’t,” I said. If I was going to be in trouble, I might as well go for broke.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Other One</title><link>/archives/1870/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1870/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sometimes things do not go as planned. The heist certainly did not. I meant it to be a simple job — masks, a few guns, fast horses, a big score at the end. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>The big dumb deputy got Jim in the back, about a minute in. By then there was smoke in the air, screaming, lots of noise. I always knew Jim would die of a bullet, most likely in the back. I think he knew the same. I should have known that the sheriff would post a deputy at the bank. It made no sense. We had spent the previous night torching the Canaveras Ranch, shot old man Canaveras, shot his ranch hands, shot the wife and children. Let one run to town with a hole in her arm, in her bloody nightgown, so as to attract attention back to the ranch. Then we rode hard around the Gap to town, and waited until the kid rode up, nearly dead, screaming and hollering about murder. &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Space Between</title><link>/archives/1862/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1862/</guid><description>&lt;p>Can a house be evil? Is it possible for a structure of wood and stone and plaster and glass to become more than the sum of its parts, in the negative sense? It certainly happens in the positive sense. Fill a house with light and love and family and that sense of comfort and well-being seems to permeate the very walls of the place. But … is it possible to architect a bad place, however inadvertently, through the unwitting intersection of board and beam?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Storage</title><link>/archives/1853/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1853/</guid><description>&lt;p>“Your honor, I’ve seen shit that would turn you white!” — Winston, Ghostbusters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There’s not a lot of work out there for a twenty-ish ex-security guard with a bad case of PTSD. And if that dumb kid was hideously scarred by a ‘serial killer’ that had carved a swathe of victims across three states and disappeared without a trace? That kid can barely get a hamburger at McDonald’s, much less gainful employment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Stairs and The Doorway</title><link>/archives/1849/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/1849/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Stairs and The Doorway&lt;br>
I don’t feel like I’m a nosy person. No more nosy than the next guy. I just have what my Ma would call an unhealthy amount of curiosity. I was the kid who climbed to the top of the big oak in the back yard, just to see what was in the crows’ nest. I was the kid who dug a hole in the back yard so deep that I hit groundwater because I was convinced there was a cave under our house, and I wanted to see it. To see.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>